Now that we've finished our game
ゲームの作成が終わったので
we need to present it to our players.
プレイヤーに提供する必要があります
One of the greatest things about Unity
Unity の素晴らしいことの 1 つに
is that once we have created
一旦ゲームを作ったら
our game we can deploy it
現在可能なプラットホームの多くに
to many of the current platforms available.
デプロイできるということです
For more detailed information on
ビルドとビルドターゲットに関する
building and build targets
詳しい情報は
please see the information linked below.
下のリンクのページをご覧ください
Before we build our game
ゲームをビルドする前に
we should save our scene.
シーンを保存します
To build our game we must
ゲームをビルドするために
first open the Build Settings window.
まず、Build Settings ウィンドウを開きます
We can do this by selecting File - Build Settings
File > Build Settings の順で選びます
or by using the key combination of
または、キーコンビネーションで
Shift + Command or Control + B.
Shift + Command/Control + B です
This brings up the Build Settings window.
これで、Build Settings ウィンドウが開きます
Our current build target is
私たちの現在のビルドのターゲットは
indicated by the Unity logo.
Unity ロゴによって示されています
The blue highlight indicates our
青いハイライトが
focus and shows us on the
選択中のプラットフォームで
right hand side the build
右側にそのビルドオプションが
options for the currently selected platform.
表示されます
We want to build a standalone application.
私たちがビルドしたいのは、スタンドアロンアプリケーションです
This is our current build target,
これが現在のビルドターゲットです
PC, Mac and Linux Standalone.
PC、Mac、Linux Standalone
We do not need to change our build target.
ビルドターゲットを変える必要はありません
If we did want to change our built target
ビルドターゲットを変えたい場合は
we can select the desired platform from the list
このリストで好きなプラットフォームを選び
and click the Switch Platforms button
ウィンドウの下の方の
at the bottom of the window.
Switch Platforms をクリックします
Let's now return our build target
さて、ビルドターゲットを
to the standalone player.
スタンドアロンプレイヤーに戻しましょう
Once we have selected our new build target
ビルドターゲットを選んだら
we need to add the scenes we want
Build Settings ウィンドウに
to build to the Build Settings window.
ビルドしたいシーンを加えます
We can add the current scene by
Add Current ボタンをクリックして
clicking the Add Current button.
現在のシーンを加えることができます
Or we can drag and drop
または、Project ビューのシーンならすべて
any scene from our project view
ドラッグ & ドロップして
in to the field at the top of the
Build Settings ウィンドウの上部のエリアに
Build Settings window.
加えることもできます
It's worth noting that we don't need
気を付けたいのは、プロジェクトのシーン
to include every scene in our project.
すべてを加える必要はないということです
We only need to include the scenes we
必要なのはゲームに
want in our game.
必要なシーンだけです
It's also possible to perform a build
Build Settings ウィンドウで
with no scenes in the Build Settings window.
シーンを加えずにビルドすることもできます
If we do this Unity will simply
その場合、Unity は単に
build our game using the
編集のために開いている現在のシーンを使って
current scene we have open for editing.
ビルドします
Now we are ready to build our game.
では、ゲームをビルドしましょう
Let's click the Build button.
Build ボタンをクリックしてください
This will bring up a dialogue box
ダイアログボックスが開き
asking us to choose a build location.
ビルドの場所を選択するよう求めます
We can build the game nearly anywhere
自分がアクセスできるドライブやネットワーク上なら
we want to on our accessible drives or network.
ほとんどどこででもゲームをビルドできます
I like to associate my build location
私はビルドの場所とプロジェクトを
with my project so I will
関連付けたいので
create a new folder inside my project
プロジェクトの内部に Builds という
called Builds.
新しいフォルダーを作成します
This folder must be placed only
このフォルダーは
on the root of our project,
Assets や Library フォルダーと並べて
along side the Assets and Library folders.
プロジェクトのルートにだけ置くようにしてください
If the build is saved in the Assets
ビルドがAssets や Library フォルダーに
or Library folder
保存されていると
Unity will attempt to treat
Unity はビルドされたファイルを
the built files as asset
アセットやライブラリファイルとして処理してしまい
or library files, which could damage the project.
プロジェクトにダメージを与える恐れがあります
When building for the Mac Unity builds a
Mac 用にビルドするときには
.app bundle, which contains all of the
Unity は関連するデータやファイルをすべて 1 つにまとめた
relevant data and files in one package.
.app バンドルをビルドします
When building for Windows,
Windows 用にビルドするときには
Unity builds a .exe file
.exe ファイルと
and a data folder, which contains all of the necessary resources.
必要なリソースすべてを含むデータフォルダーをビルドします
To keep things organised I like to make
整理しておくために Builds フォルダー内に
a separate folder for each build
それぞれのビルドに対し
within the Builds folder.
別々のフォルダーを作ります
I'll make a folder called UFO Game Build 1
UFO Game Build 1 というフォルダーを作り
And save the build inside it.
ビルドをその中に保存します
Unity will now build the application
これで、Unity はアプリケーションをビルドして
and save it to our Builds folder.
Builds フォルダーに保存します
To run the game, simply run the
ゲームをするには、実行アプリを実行するだけです。
executable application, and now we are running our game.
今、まさにゲームを実行しているところです
And we win!
そして、勝利しました！
So in these assignments we have learned how to
このレッスンでは
create new game objects,
新しいゲームオブジェクトを作成し
how to position them in the scene,
シーンへそれらを配置し
add new components to them,
オブジェクトへコンポーネントを加え
and write our own custom behaviours
カスタムビヘイビアの
for them using simple scripting.
簡単なスクリプトを作りました
We've seen how to use cameras,
また、カメラ、
2D colliders, 2D triggers
2D コライダー、2D トリガー
and 2D rigid bodies.
2D rigid body の使い方も学びました
We can collect and count objects.
オブジェクトを取得して数えることもできます
Though this is a very simple example
とても単純な例題でしたが
it covers a large set of basic
Unity の使い方を理解するのに
subjects important to understanding
重要な基本的な項目を
how to use Unity.
広範囲にカバーしています
For continued learning about how to use Unity
Unity の使い方を引き続き学びたい場合は
check the Learn site for more lessons,
「Unity を学ぶ」のサイトで
assignments and projects.
チュートリアルやプロジェクトをご覧ください
Thanks for watching.
どうもありがとうございました